KENGO ICHIKI

市來 健吾

(kengoichiki@gmail.com)

I worked in both Academia and IT company for 10+ years respectively.

• Engineer (Programmer): May 2009 - May 2023

• Researcher (Physicist): April 1997 – January 2009

In last 5 years, I'm working on AI related R&D projects.

ENGINEER EXPERIENCE

I worked at ZENKEI corporation (https://zenkei.com) from May 2009 to May 2023 as a research engineer (programmer) at the beginning and as the chief in 5 years. It is a small company with 14 members in total. In 2023, I was leading two teams (4 + 2 people).

Due to company restructuring at the end of April 2023, the company closed Research & Development division, which I am the head. Then, I left the company.

Role (in 2023)

- Team Leader of Research & Development team (4 members)
- Team Leader of 3D Project team (2 members)

Work Projects

- Re-implementation of the image conversion engine (2009 2010)
- Development of panorama stitching program (2009 2011)
- Prototyping 3D 360 camera device (2010 2015)
- Building AI model for VR player generation (2017 2018)
- Application of AI to our services (data analysis, MLOps, etc) (2018 2023)
- Development of panorama-to-3D creation system (manually) (2019 2023)

Awards

• 10th prize at Kaggle "Kuzushiji Recognition" competition (from July 19 to October 15, 2019) https://www.kaggle.com/competitions/kuzushiji-recognition

Public Projects

- Lecturer for "AI SEMINAR" (2018)
- Organiser of "AI FORUM" (2019 to date)

Patents

• WO2016/208539 (Japan and China)
"Binocular stereoscopic image providing method, distribution device, and camera unit"
(https://patents.google.com/patent/JPW02016208539A1/en)

Programming Skills

- C and C++
- $\bullet~$ C# for . NET framework
- Python
 - TensorFlow
 - PyTorch

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

I studied in theoretical and computational physics and got Ph.D. in 1997. Since then til January 2009, I had been working as a research scientists on theoretical and computational physics.

Education

- B.Sc., Physics, Tohoku University (March 1992)
- M.Sc., Physics, Tohoku University (March 1994)
- Ph.D., Physics, Tohoku University (March 1997)

Awards

- Fellowship of the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (April 1996 March 1998)
- Fellowship of the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (April 1998 – March 2001)

Experience

• Kyoto University, Dept. Human Enrivonm. (Physics),

Kyoto, Japan

Postdoctoral fellow (supervisor: Hisao Hayakawa)

(April 1997 – September 1997)

• California Institute of Technology, Chemical Engineering,

Pasadena, CA, USA

Postdoctoral scholar (supervisor: John F. Brady)

(September 1997 – September 1999)

• Kyoto University, Dept. Human Enrivonm. (Physics),

Kyoto, Japan

Postdoctoral fellow (supervisor: Hisao Hayakawa)

(October 1999 – March 2001)

• University of Twente, Applied Physics,

Enschede, the Netherlands

Postdoctoral fellow (supervisor: Detlef Lohse)

(May 2001 - April 2002)

• The Johns Hopkins University, Mechanical Engineering,

Baltimore, MD, USA

Postdoctoral fellow (supervisor: Andrea Prosperetti)

(May 2002 – August 2004)

• The University of Western Ontario, Chemistry,

London, ON, Canada

Postdoctoral fellow (supervisor: Styliani Consta)

(September 2004 – September 2006)

• The University of Western Ontario, Applied Mathematics,

London, ON, Canada

Postdoctoral fellow (supervisor: David J. Jeffrey)

(November 2006)

• University of Alberta, Mechanical Engineering and National Institute for Nanotechnology,

Edmonton, AB, Canada

Publication List

- 1. **K.Ichiki** and H.Hayakawa, Int. J. Mod. Phys. B (1993) Vol.7 pp.1899-1911 "Simulation of granular particles in flow by the Stokesian dynamics method"
- H.Hayakawa and K.Ichiki, Phys. Rev. E 51,(1995) pp.R3815-R3818 "Statistical theory of disordered suspensions"
- 3. **K.Ichiki** and H.Hayakawa, Phys. Rev. E 52,(1995) pp.658-670 "Dynamical simulation of fluidized beds: Hydrodynamically interacting granular particles"
- 4. **K.Ichiki** and H.Hayakawa, Phys. Rev. E 57,(1998) pp.1990-1996 "Analysis of statistical quantities in simulation of fluidized beds"
- 5. **K.Ichiki**, Prog. Theor. Phys. Suppl. (2000) No.138 pp.736-737 "Fast calculation of hydrodynamic interaction among particles in the Stokes flows"
- 6. **K.Ichiki** and J.F.Brady, Phys. Fluids (2001) **13** 350-353 (DOI:10.1063/1.1331320) "Many-body effects and matrix-inversion in low-Reynolds-number hydrodynamics"
- 7. **K.Ichiki**, J. Fluid Mech. (2002) **452**, pp. 231-262 (DOI:10.1017/S0022112001006735) "Improvement of the Stokesian Dynamics method for systems with finite number of particles"
- 8. **K.Ichiki** and A.Prosperetti, Phys. Fluids (2004) **16** 2483-2496 (DOI:10.1063/1.1734951) "Faxén-like relations for a non-uniform suspension"
- 9. **K.Ichiki**, Powder Technology Handbook, Third Edition (ISBN: 1574447823, CRC Press, January 13, 2006) "**V.21.7 Transport Properties**"
- 10. Q.Zhang, **K.Ichiki** and A.Prosperetti, J. Comp. Phys. (2006) Vol.212, pp.247-267 "On the Computation of ensemble averages for spatially non-uniform particle systems"
- 11. A.Prosperetti, Q.Zhang and **K.Ichiki**, J. Fluid Mech. (2006) Vol.554, pp.125-146 "The stress system in a suspension of heavy particles: antisymmetric contribution"
- 12. A.Prosperetti, **K.Ichiki** and Q.Zhang, Multiphase Sci. Tech (2006) Vol.18, pp.135-154 "Systematic Approach to Closure Relations for Disperse Particle Flows: Inter-Phase Force"
- 13. **K.Ichiki** and S.Consta, J. Phys. Chem. B (2006) **110**(39), pp.19168 19175 (DOI:10.1021/jp062222a) "Disintegration mechanisms of charged aqueous nanodroplets studied by simulations and analytical models"
- K.Ichiki, A.E.Kobryn, and A.Kovalenko, J. Comput. Theor. Nanosci. (2008) 5(10), pp. 2004-2021 (DOI:10.1166/jctn.2008.1007)
 "Targeting Transport Properties in Nanofluidics: Hydrodynamic Interaction among Slip Surface Nanoparticles in Solution"
- A. E. Kobryn, K.Ichiki, and A. Kovalenko Int. J. Quantum Chem. (2009) 109(8) pp.1666-1671 "Thermodynamic dependences of slip length for nanofluidic flows over crystalline surfaces: predictions of molecular theory of solvation"
- 16. K.Ichiki, A.E.Kobryn, and A.Kovalenko, arXiv:1302.0461 "Resistance functions for two unequal spheres in linear flow at low Reynolds number with the Navier slip boundary condition"

Research Interests

My research interests (in those days) were

- Theory of hydrodynamics in low Reynolds number flows (nanofluidics)
- Development of computational algorithm for hydrodynamic interaction of particles in viscous fluid called Stokesian dynamics
- Application of Fast Multipole Method to Stokesian dynamics
- Formulating and solving exact solution of hydrodynamic interaction between two particles in low Reynolds number flow
- Molecular dynamics for charged nano droplets

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Open Source Projects

- WaoN project (https://github.com/kichiki/WaoN)
- RYUON project (https://kichiki.github.io/ryuon/)

(GitHub account: https://github.com/kichiki)

Books (self publishing)

- "Music and Math music transcription for dummies" (2020) in Japanese https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0C7JFHTDF
 - This is backstory of my open source project "WaoN"
- "Exact Computation" (2021) in Japanese
 https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0C7JCBC6P
 This is backstory of "RYUON twobody"
 and my paper https://arxiv.org/abs/1302.0461.
- "ZAM ZENKEI AI FORUM, Volume 1" (2021) in Japanese https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/BOBHLFMXJH Summary of the event "ZENKEI AI FORUM"
- "ZAM ZENKEI AI FORUM, Volume 2" (2022) in Japanese https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/BOBHG8GJDR Summary of the event "ZENKEI AI FORUM"
- "Essay: Music and Math Podcast macht frei" (2023) in Japanese https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/B0C7JG3GYS
 This is transcription of my personal podcast https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/music-and-math

YouTube & Podcasts

- "HELLO! AI FORUM" (former "ZENKEI AI FORUM") https://www.youtube.com/@hello-ai-forum https://hello-ai-forum.github.io/
- "Music and Math" podcast https://podcasters.spotify.com/pod/show/music-and-math